(Klaxon blaring)
(screams)
무슨 짓이야?
What the hell?
비상 대비 훈련이야
Emergency preparedness drill.
- 뭐야
- 알면서 왜 그래
- Oh, no, come on!
- Yeah, you know how it works.
석 달에 한번은 해야 돼
Once a quarter,
keep our readiness up.
일어나라 잠꾸러기야
Now, rise and shine,
sleepy head.
마을 전체의 반은
죽었을 거야
Half the town is probably dead.
자물쇠를 채우던지 해야지
I have to get
a lock for my door.
이번 훈련은 너도 좋아할걸
I think you'll like
the drill tonight.
재밌게 준비해봤어
I've tried to make it fun.
각 카드에
Each of these cards
세계 종말을
다르게 예측해봤어
contains a detailed scenario
of a possible apocalyptic event.
산불도 있고
Everything from wild fires
캐나다의
기습 공격까지
to a surprise invasion
by Canada.
재앙을 하나 골라봐
Pick a catastrophe,
any catastrophe.
캐나다는 캘리포니아를
침략하지 않을 거야
Sheldon, Canada is not going
to invade California.
그래?
Yeah, really?
You think those hippies
워싱턴과 오레곤의
히피들이 막을 수 있을까?
in Washington and Oregon
can stop them?
알았어
Fine.
어디 보자
All righty!
규모 8.2의 강진이
패서디나를 강타
"An 8.2 magnitude earthquake
devastates Pasadena,
건물들은 무너져 내리고
"reducing mighty
edifices to dust,
도시는 불에 타오르며
"engulfing the city in flames.
거리는 피바다로 변한다
"The streets flow with blood
죽어가는 시민들의
울음으로 가득찬다
and echo with the cries
of the wounded."
탁월한 선택이야
Oh, excellent choice.
안전모랑 안전조끼 착용해
Now, put on your hardhat
and safety vest.
신난다
Oh, fun.
또 쪽팔리게
집앞에서 이래야 하나
I get to spend another night
in front of our apartment
'빌리지 피플'
복장 같잖아
dressed like one
of the Village People.
석 달에 한번 하는 농담인데
You make that joke
every three months.
아직도 이해가 안 가
I still don't get it.
레너드, 잠깐
Leonard... wait.
뭐 하는 거야?
What are you doing?
나도 몰라,
내가 뭘 하고 있지?
I don't know,
what am I doing?
주변을 둘러봐
Look around you--
가상적인 유리 파편을
조심해야지
there's hypothetical
broken glass everywhere.
보조 기구 없이
종말을 대면하겠다고?
Really? You're going
to face Armageddon
without your orthotics?
맘대로 해
Your choice.
가상 여진이다!
Uh-oh, hypothetical aftershock!
(yells)
(thud)
Aah!
그러니까 안전모를 써야지
And that's why we wear hardhats.
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
DC 기타 미국드라마 갤러리
The Big Bang Theory 5x15
The Friendship Contraction
Original Air Date on February 2, 2012
자막 공대언니
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
NASA에서 공식 발표를 했어
Check it out--
press release
from NASA.
31원정대가 이번 봄에
Um, "Expedition 31
will launch this spring
국제우주정거장으로
출발한다
"to the International
Space Station.
이번 원정대는
선장 톰 '톰보' 존슨
"Crew members will include
Commander Tom 'Tombo' Johnson,
비행사 마이크
'슈퍼노바' 노바체릭
"Astronaut
Mike 'Supernova' Novacelik
그리고 탑승 과학 기술자
하워드 왈로위츠로 이뤄졌다
and Payload Specialist
Howard Wolowitz."
(giggles)
유대교 회당
뉴스레터에도 알려야지
This is going right into
my synagogue's newsletter.
우주 비행사가 될거면
D-Dude, if you're
going to be an astronaut,
멋진 별명 좀 골라봐
you need to pick
a cool nickname.
내가 고르는게 아냐
I don't get to pick it.
누군가 지어줘야해
The other guys
have to give it to me.
내 별명은
'브라운 다이너마이트'
Oh. If I had one,
it would be "Brown Dynamite."
내 말 못 들었어?
Are you not listening to me?
다른 비행사들이
지어주는 거라고
The other astronauts
have to give you your nickname.
눈은 뜨고 있냐?
Are you not looking at me?
내가 바로
'브라운 다이너마이트'잖아
I am Brown Dynamite.
커피에 왜
설탕을 6개나 넣어?
Why do you put six
sugars in your coffee?
식당에서 각성제를
구하기는 어려워서
Because the cafeteria
doesn't offer
little packets
of methamphetamine.
어젯밤 또 훈련했나봐
Emergency drill night
last night, huh?
잘했어?
- Uh-huh.
- How'd you do?
내가 정확히 알려주지
I'll tell you
exactly how he did.
준비성은 수준 미달이고
"Readiness:
unsatisfactory.
대부분 지시를 무시하며
"Follows direction: barely.
태도는 좀 과했어
"Attitude: a little too much.
종합적으로 봤을 때
"Overall:
큰 불에 타죽을
뿐만 아니라
"not only will he probably die
in a fiery inferno,
계속된 투정으로
주변인의 기분을 잡칠 거야
"his incessant whining
would most certainly spoil
everyone else's day."
너무 피곤해서
정신이 없다
You know what, I can't
even think straight.
집에 가야겠어
I'm going home.
이 미친놈은
너네가 집에 태워다줘
Will one of you guys give
this nutbag a ride back later?
안돼
You can't go home.
4시에 치과에 데려다 줘야지
You have to take me
to the dentist at 4:00.
버스 타고 가면 안돼?
Oh... can't you take
the bus to the dentist?
물론 되지
Of course I can.
It's coming back,
마취 상태라
돌아올 때가 문제야
under the residual effects
of the anesthesia,
that's the problem.
2년 전에
Two years ago,
잇몸 관리 후
버스를 탄 줄 알았는데
after a deep gum cleaning,
I thought I got on a bus
멕시코로 가는 크루즈더라
but somehow wound up
on a booze cruise to Mexico.
잇몸 관리인데 마취를 해?
They put you under
for a cleaning?
안 그러면 내가 물거든
Yeah, they have to--
I'm a biter.
알아서 해, 쉘든
Whatever, Sheldon.
I'm exhausted.
못 데려다 주겠다
I'm not taking you
to the dentist.
이봐, 틀렸어
Wrong, sir.
룸메이트 계약서 섹션 37b
Wrong. Under section 37-B
of the Roommate Agreement--
기타 의무 중
"Miscellaneous Duties"--
you are obligated
넌 나를 치과에
데려다줄 의무가 있어
to take me to the dentist.
'의심스러운 유제품
대신 맡아주기' 밑에
See? It's right here after
"providing a confirmation sniff
on questionable dairy products."
룸메이트 계약서는
이제 지겨워
You know what, I am sick
of the Roommate Agreement.
(gasps)
말이 안돼
It's ridiculous.
난 룸메이트지,
기사가 아냐
I'm your roommate,
not your chauffeur.
난 그렇게
한가하지 않아
You know, I had
better things to do yesterday
동네 모형기차 가게가
예전같지 않다고
than drive you all the way
to the "good" model train store
in Garden Grove
because the one in Pasadena
더 먼 가게로
태워다달라 하다니
has gotten
"too big for its britches."
사실이거든
Well, it has.
모두 동의할걸
Ask anybody.
상관 없어
I don't care.
난 그만할래
I'm done.
잠깐
Hold on.
209항을 적용하는 거야?
Are you saying that you
want to invoke Clause 209?
그게 뭔지도 몰라
I don't know what that is,
집에 가서 자도
되는 거라면 써야지
but if it means I can go home
and sleep, then yes.
잘 생각해
Think carefully here.
우리 사이의
우정이 중단되고
Clause 209 suspends
our friendship,
룸메이트 계약서를
간소화시키지
and strips down the
Roommate Agreement to
its bare essentials.
서로에게 지켜야
하는 의무는
Our responsibilities
toward each other would
월세, 공과금
only be rent, utilities
그리고 고개를
끄덕이는 정도의
and a perfunctory
chin jut of recognition
형식적인 인사 뿐이야
as we pass in the hall.
어이
'Sup?
서명은 어디에 할까?
Where do I sign?
여기
Right here.
손가락으로
Use your finger.
됐다
There. Done.
All right.
우리는 이제 친구가 아냐
That's it. We are
now no longer companions,
절친도 끝이라고
boon or otherwise.
그냥 아는 사람이지
We are not merely
acquaintances.
토이스토리 주제가를
반대로 말하면
To amend the words
of Toy Story--
넌 내 친구가 아냐
"You have not got
a friend in me."
집에 가서
낮잠이나 자야겠다
I'm gonna go home
and take a nap.
신경 껐으니
다른 사람한테 말해
Yeah, well, tell it
to someone who cares.
NASA에서 좋은 소식을 받았어
I got pretty exciting
NASA news today.
다음 주 휴스턴에서
오리엔테이션을 한대
Next week I fly to Houston
for orientation
무중력 배출 훈련도 있어
and zero-gravity
elimination drills.
무슨 뜻이야?
What does that mean?
우주에서 똥 싸는
법을 배우는 거야
He's gonna learn
to poop in space.
할, 팟 베이의 문을 열어
*스페이스 오디세이 대사
Open the pod bay
doors, HAL.
브라운 다이너마이트는
너한테도 어울린다
Maybe your nickname
should be "Brown Dynamite."
안녕, 친구들
Hello, dear friends.
호프스태더 박사도
And Dr. Hofstadter.
왓썹
'Sup?
미안
My apologies.
더 일찍 올 수 있었는데
I would've been here sooner,
버스가 다른 사람들을
태우려고 계속 멈췄어
but the bus kept stopping
for other people to get on it.
만두 하나 남겼어
I saved you a dumpling.
이렇게 날 챙겨주다니
Oh, your concern
for me is touching.
내일 치과에 데려다
줄 때도 똑같이 하면 돼
It will serve you well
when you take me to
the dentist tomorrow.
미안한데 난 바빠
I'm sorry, Sheldon, I'm busy.
중독 관련 연구를
진행 중이야
I'm right in the middle
of my addiction study.
실험실이 알코올 중독
원숭이로 가득 찼어
I've got a lab
full of alcoholic monkeys,
내일은 무알코올 맥주로
바꾸는 날이야
and tomorrow's the day
we switch them to O'Doul's.
여자친구로서
내 요구를 들어줘야지
You're my girlfriend
and you're not going to cater
to my every need?
예전같지 않아
Oh, where'd the magic go?
쉘든, 그런 목적으로
여자친구를 사귀지 않잖아
Sheldon, that's not
what girlfriends are for.
넌 원래 목적도
모르는 것 같으니
Although, you don't use them
for what they're for,
할 말이 없다
so what do I know?
하워드는 나한테
쇼핑을 시키거나
Howard doesn't make
me do his shopping
치과에 데려다 달라거나
or take him to the dentist
세탁물 수거를
시키지 않아
or pick up his
dry cleaning, right?
당연하지
Absolutely.
엄마 허리가 약해지면
네 차례야
But when Ma's hips
give out, you're up, kid.
에이미가 바쁘다면
Well, if Amy's too busy,
that gives the rest of you
너네한테도 기회를 줄게
an opportunity to
make my life easier,
다음에 쓸 회고록에
주석을 달아주지
thus assuring yourselves
a footnote in my memoirs,
임시 제목은
You're Welcome, Mankind
tentatively entitled
You're Welcome, Mankind.
시작하자
All right, then,
맡고 싶은 일이
있으면 소리 질러
just shout when you hear
the task you want to undertake.
치과
Uh, dentist.
한 바퀴 돌지 뭐
Okay, w-we can
circle back to that one.
구두 굽을 교체해야 되는데
Um, well, who wants
to take me Wednesday morning
수요일 아침에
같이 갈 사람?
to get new heels
put on my dress shoes?
누구 없어?
Anyone?
이런 기회를 놓치다니
Oh. That one had hoot
written all over it.
다음은 피부과
Um, all right,
uh, dermatologist.
알레르기과
Allergist.
족부외과
Podiatrist.
이발소?
Supercuts?
이번은 좀 재밌는 건데
Okay, okay, here's a fun one.
액자가 필요하고
Um, I need a new picture frame
스웨덴 미트볼이 먹고 싶어
and I have a hankering
for Swedish meatballs.
나랑 같이
이케아 갈 사람?
Who wants to spend the day
with me at IKEA?
미트볼은 맛있던데
Their meatballs
are pretty good.
뭐라고?
What's that?
아냐
Nothing, nothing.
안녕, 스튜어트
Hello, Stuart.
Oh, hey, Sheldon.
뭐 찾는 거 있어?
Can I help you find
something today?
아니
No, no.
집에 있다가
I was just sitting at home
내가 9번째로
좋아하는 사람이
thinking about how it
might be nice to catch up
어떻게 지내는지
궁금해졌어
with my ninth favorite person.
9번째?
Ninth?
한 단계 올라갔어
You moved up one.
소말리아에 사는 펜팔이
해적에 납치됐거든
My pen pal in Somalia
was kidnapped by pirates.
잘 지내?
So, uh... how are you?
별로야
Uh... not so good.
정신과 의사가 자살했어
My shrink just
killed himself and...
유서에는 나를 탓했지
blamed me in the note.
좋아
Great. Great.
가족은 잘 지내?
So, what's new
with your family?
엄마는?
살아 계셔?
How's your mother?
Is she alive?
응
Yeah.
아빠는?
And your father? Alive?
응
Yes.
할아버지, 할머니는?
How about your grandparents,
they alive?
아니
No.
유감이다
Oh, I'm so sorry for your loss.
분위기 전환을 위해
On a cheerier note,
오후에 치과
가려고 하는데
I have a teeth-cleaning
appointment this afternoon.
날 데려다 주지
않을래, 친구야?
What do you say you
take me over there, buddy boy?
치과에 데려다 달라고?
I'm sorry, you want me
to take you to the dentist?
보장을 하기는 어렵지만
Yes. Now, I can't
make any promises,
부탁을 들어주면
but that's the sort of thing
8번으로 한 단계
오를 가능성도 있어
that gets a fella
on the short list
for the number eight
friend slot.
쉘든, 난 근무 중이야
Sheldon, I'm working.
데려다 줄 시간 없어
I can't take you
to the dentist.
그리고 분명히 강조하는데
Also-- and I can't
stress this enough--
데려다 주고 싶지도 않아
I don't want to take you
to the dentist.
친구들은 서로
도와주는 건데
Can't help a friend out
in a time of need, huh?
네 당담의사가
왜 죽었는지 알겠다
I see where your
therapist was coming from.
비행사 별명이 떠올랐어
Ooh, ooh! What about we
make your astronaut nickname
하워드 버즈 왈로위츠
Howard "Buzz" Wolowitz?
버즈는 안돼
You can't do "Buzz."
누가 쓰고 있잖아
"Buzz" is taken.
버즈 라이트이어는
실존 인물이 아니야
Buzz Lightyear is not real.
장난감을 말한 게 아냐
No, that's not what
I'm talking about.
버즈가 자신이 진짜인 줄
알았을 때를 말하는 건가?
Well, are you talking about
when he thought he was real?
아니
No.
그럼 크래쉬는?
Okay, um...
how about "Crash"?
하워드 크래쉬 왈로위츠
Howard "Crash" Wolowitz.
우주에 가는데
Yeah, terrific.
The other astronauts
'추락'이라는 별명을
가진 놈을 누가 데려가?
would love to go hurtling
through space
with a guy named "Crash."
그렇다면...
All right, um, how about...
로켓 맨?
Oh, how about "Rocket Man"?
괜찮다,
하워드 로켓맨 왈로위츠
That's not bad,
Howard "Rocket Man" Wolowitz.
좋긴 좋은데
Yeah, it's great,
but I told you,
내가 고르는 게 아니라고
I don't get to pick
my nickname.
다른 비행사들이
지어주는 거야
It has to come from
the other astronauts.
지어주도록 만들면 되지
Maybe there's a way to get
them to come up with it.
어떻게?
Like how?
한때는 던컨 요요를
들고 다녔어
Once I tried carrying
around a Duncan yo-yo,
애들이 던컨이라
불러주길 바랬어
hoping the other kids would
start calling me Duncan.
효과는?
Did it work?
아니,
꼬랑내라고 부르던데
No, they ended up
calling me Sock Mouth.
요요를 뺏기고
Because they took away my yo-yo
내 입에
양말을 쳐박았어
and stuffed their socks
in my mouth.
벨소리를 '로켓 맨'으로 바꾸고
Okay, uh, what if we make
"Rocket Man" your ringtone,
비행사들이랑
같이 있을 때
and the next time you
talk to those guys,
내가 전화를 걸게
I'll call you and
they'll hear it.
씨를 심는 거야
Plant the seed.
나쁘지 않네
That's actually not
a terrible plan.
브라운 다이너마이트니까
They don't call me
"Brown Dynamite" for nothing.
'Sup?
치과에는 갔어?
Hey, did you ever make it
to the dentist?
필요 없어
Not necessary. No.
집을 방문해주는
치아 관리사를 찾았어
I found a service that'll
send a van to your house
for a teeth cleaning.
주로 개를 대상으로 하지만
Mostly they cater
to dogs, but...
전화를 해보니
꽤 호의적이었어
...the fellow on the phone
seemed to have an open mind.
이봐, 쉘든
All right, Sheldon,
치과에 꼭 가야한다면
if you need me to take you
to the dentist,
내가 데려다 줄게
I will take you to the dentist.
드디어 정신을 차리고
Are you suggesting that
you've come to your senses
룸메이트 계약서를
다시 성립시켜
and wish to reestablish
the mutual benefits that stem
서로 이익을 챙기자는 거야?
from full participation
in the Roommate Agreement?
응
Absolutely.
네가 서른이 되도록
If you admit that
you're a 30-year-old man
혼자 사는 법도
못 배웠다고 인정하면
who's incapable
of functioning on his own.
꼬랑내가 선방했네
Ooh, Sock Mouth's
got him on the ropes.
그런 건 인정 못해
I will admit nothing
of the sort.
실례 좀 할게
And now if you'll excuse me,
치과 의사한테
상담을 하려고
I have
to call my dentist and see
샴푸랑 손톱 관리도
받을 수 있는지
if I can also get my hair
shampooed and my nails clipped.
(dramatic music plays on TV)
(music stops)
(knocking on door)
다행이다,
너네도 불이 안 들어오네
Oh, good, your power's out, too.
그게 뭐가 다행이야?
Why is that good?
지난 달에
(sighs)
Because last month,
전기세 대신 스타벅스
기프트카드를 보냈어
I sent the electric company
a Starbucks gift card,
사과문이랑
브라만 입은 사진 몇 장도
an apology note, and a few
snapshots of me in a bra.
정전이다
(Klaxon sounds)
Power failure.
정전 행동요령을 따르시오
Implementing
power-failure protocol.
바닥에 칠했던
야광 비상탈출 안내판은?
What happened to all your glow-
in-the-dark-emergency-exit stuff
you had painted on the floor?
발암성 물질이 있더라고
Oh, that was
wildly carcinogenic.
아무튼
Anyway...
이젠 친구가 아니라
넌 혜택을 못 받겠군
it's too bad you're
no longer entitled
to the full benefits
of my friendship,
난 이런 비상사태를
대비해 철저히 준비했거든
because I happen to be
extremely prepared
for such an emergency.
헤드라이트로 비추는 건
보지 말도록
Please try not to see
anything by this light.
널 위한 게 아냐
It's not for you.
그냥 정전이잖아,
곧 다시 들어오겠지
It's just a blackout; I'm sure
the power will be back on soon.
도너 일행 중 그렇게
말한 멍청이가 있겠지
And I'm sure some fool
in the Donner party
눈이 곧 멈출 거라고
said the snow would
stop any day now.
그 놈이 제일 먼저
먹혔다면 좋겠네
I like to think
they ate him first.
집에 양초가 좀 있어
You know, I got some candles
in my apartment.
정전 중에 초를?
But candles?!
During a blackout?!
미쳤어?
불 나면 어쩌려고
Are you mad?
That's a fire hazard.
패서디나 수도전력국은
No, Pasadena
Water and Power recommends
안전한 야광
스틱을 권장했어
the far safer glow stick.
그게 야광 스틱이야?
You call that
a glow stick?
이 정도는 되야지
That is a glow stick.
가자
Come on, let's go.
잠시만
Before you go,
consider this.
해양 전력 공급소가 있어서
Not only do I have a deep-cycle
marine battery power source
엔터테인먼트 시설을
평소처럼 활용할 수 있어
which is more than capable
of running our
entertainment system,
BBC 시리즈
적색왜성 61편과
I also have
all 61 episodes
of the BBC series Red Dwarf...
피들페들도 있어
and Fiddle-Faddle.
맘껏 즐길 수 있어
All yours
룸메이트 계약서를
다시 성립시키면
if you're willing to reinstate
the Roommate Agreement.
우리 집에 와인 있어,
심심하면 뽁뽁이 터치자
I've got wine at my place and
some bubble wrap we could pop.
곧 올 거야
Oh, he'll be back.
와인과 어둠 속에 여인이라
Wine and a girl in the dark--
지루해 죽을 걸
he's gonna be bored
out of his mind.
와인과 뽁뽁이를 위하여
To wine and bubble wrap.
(popping)
쉘든의 역삼투압 장치
시연도 보고 싶지 않아
And to not having to watch
Sheldon demonstrate
his reverse osmosis machine
오줌을 식수로 바꾸는 거야
that converts urine
into drinking water.
걸스카웃 친구
태미가 말했는데
You know, in Girl Scouts,
Tammie Dineesha said
스타킹으로도 가능하대
you could do that
with panty hose.
안 되더라
Boy, was she wrong.
섹스할까?
Anyway, you want
to make out?
아직 베타 테스트 중이라
I thought because our
relationship's in a beta test,
천천히 하는 거 아니였어?
you wanted to
take things slow.
그래
Okay.
천천히 애무부터 할까?
Do you want to make out slow?
입 속에 달팽이가
있는 것처럼 느껴질 거야
I can go so slow it'll be like
there's a snail in your mouth.
Ugh.
이것 말고는 할일이 없어,
넌 운이 좋다
Well, lucky for you, there's
nothing else to do right now.
잠시만, 레너드
Excuse me, Leonard.
원래 노크하고
들어오지 않아?
Since when don't you knock?
네 유일한 장점이였는데
It's like the only
good thing about you.
그런 호의를
베풀 시간 없어
Social niceties
have been suspended, Leonard.
비상사태라고
We're in a state of a emergency.
우리는 어둠의
혼란에 빠져있어
The world has
descended into darkened turmoil.
야만과 무법의 세계야
Lawlessness and savagery
are the order of the day.
무슨 일인데?
Fine, what is it?
마시멜로를 굽고 있어
I'm making s'mores.
마시멜로 냄새를 맡고
놀랄까봐 알려주는 거야
I wanted to alert you
in case you smelled
caramelizing marshmallows
근처 캔디 공장에
화재가 발생한게 아니라고
and thought a nearby
candy factory was on fire.
마시멜로?
맛있게 먹어
S'mores, huh?
Good for you.
같이 맛있게
먹을 수도 있어
Yes, or good for us
여기에 서명을 하고
if you sign here
룸메이트 계약서를
원상복귀한다면
and reinstate
the full Roommate Agreement.
아냐, 됐어
No, thanks. I'm good.
정말?
Really?
그래
Huh! Okay.
그럼 혼자서 먹지 뭐
In that case, I will have
a s'more by myself.
그리고 더 먹을 거야
And then I'm gonna have s'more.
혼자서
By myself.
- 저런
- 동정하지 마
- Aw.
- No, don't "aw" him.
다 자기 잘못이야
He brought this all
on himself.
슬퍼하잖아
But he's sad.
아니, 미친 거야
No, he's crazy.
가끔 미친 상태가
슬픔으로 보이기도 하는데
Sometimes crazy
looks like sad
속으면 안돼
so it'll suck you back in.
친구를 그리워하는 것 같아
I think he misses
his little buddy.
알았어
Fine.
약속은 지켜줘
But mark my words,
천천히 섹스를
하기로 했잖아
this frustrating, bogus teenage
make-out session is not over.
(popping)
초는 위험하다며
I thought you said
candles were dangerous.
이건 분젠버너야
This is a Bunsen burner.
난 과학자야
I'm a scientist;
I know what I'm doing.
젠장
Oh, drat.
Aww.
오줌 4리터로
만든 물인데
It took me a gallon of urine
to make that water.
쉘든, 그만하자
Listen, Sheldon, this is stupid.
친구로 못 남을
이유가 없잖아
I don't see why we can't
be friends.
치과에 데려다 주고
And I'm willing to
drive you around
친구로 도와주고 싶어
and help you out with stuff.
하지만 계약서에
얽매이고 싶지 않아
I just don't want to do it
because of some
silly Roommate Agreement.
뭘 제안하는 거야?
What are you proposing?
예전처럼 하자고
That we go back to
the way things were.
널 위해 뭔가 해주며
But when I do
something for you,
고마움을 표현하면 좋겠어
you show a little
appreciation.
어떻게?
And how would I do that?
고맙다고 말해
You say "thank you."
매번?
Every time?
불가능하지 않잖아
It's not crazy.
역제안을 할게
Counter-proposal.
룸메이트 계약서를
원상복귀하고
We reinstate the full
Roommate Agreement
조항을 추가하는 거야
with the following addendum:
어버이 날과 비슷하게
in the spirit of Mother's Day
or Father's Day,
하루를 지정해서
once a year, we set aside
a day to celebrate
너한테 고마워할게
all your contributions
to my life,
셀제로 받은 도움과
네가 착각한 것도 포함
both actual and imagined by you.
레너드의 날이라 부르자
We could call it Leonard's Day.
좀 괜찮은데
I kind of like
the sound of that.
그렇겠지
Of course you do.
너와 관련된 거라면
다 좋아하잖아
It's about you,
like everything else.
다행이다
Oh, thank goodness.
물 한 컵을
만들 수 있겠군
I don't think I had it in me
to make another glass of water.
레너드의 날에는
네가 아침 차리는 거야?
So, do I get breakfast
in bed on Leonard's Day?
아니
No.
네 자리에 앉아도 돼?
Can I sit in your spot?
아니
No.
온도 조절해도 돼?
Can I control the thermostat?
아니
No.
카드는 받아?
Do I get a card?
물론이지
Of course you get a card.
레너드의 날이잖아
It's Leonard's Day.
관리인이 알려줬어
Hey, guys, the building
manager said
누가 스위치를 내려서
잠깐 전기가 나간 거래
the reason
the power went out is
someone went
down into the basement
and just pulled the
main breaker switch.
그렇군
Really.
누가 그랬을까, 쉘든?
Who do you think
did that, Sheldon?
모르지
Oh, I don't know.
누군지 모르지만
But whoever
that mystery man was,
참 고마운 사람이네
you should be
eternally grateful,
그 분이 없었다면
레너드의 날도 없잖아
for without him, there would
be no Leonard's Day.
레너드의 날?
Leonard's Day?
부담 갖지 마
Oh, no pressure.
카드 하나 주면 끝이야
Just get him a crummy card,
you're good.
벨소리 좀 들어보자
All right, test my ring tone.
엘튼 존 - 로켓 맨
(Elton John's
"Rocket Man" plays)
노래 좋다
- That really is a good song.
- Oh, yeah.
엘튼 존 경인 이유가 있어
There's a reason
he's Sir Elton John.
아무나 기사 작위를
받는 게 아냐
They don't make you a knight
Wake Me Up Before You Go Go
같은 노래면 안돼
for writing "Wake Me Up
Before You Go Go."
하워드, 아침 먹을 거니?
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Howard, are you
coming down for breakfast?!
NASA랑 화상 회의 있다고요
Ma, I told you I have
a video conference with NASA!
귀찮게 하지 말아요
I said don't bother me!
대단한 비행사님이시네
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Oh! Listen to
Mr. Big Shot Astronaut!
비행사님 말 좀 들어요
Yes, please listen
to Mr. Big Shot Astronaut!
(Skype rings)
안녕하세요
Hey, good morning.
일찍 일어나서 고마워
Hey, Howard,
thanks for getting up so early.
물론 그래야죠,
매시미노 박사님
No problem, Dr. Massimino.
매스라고 불러도 돼
The guys here call me Mass.
매스, 멋지네요
Mass!
That's a cool nickname.
Force = mass x acceleration
'Cause force equals mass
times acceleration.
Yeah.
그냥 매시미노를
줄인 거야
It's just short
for Massimino.
아무튼 오늘 얘기할 건...
Anyway, the plan for this
morning is to go over the...
(Elton John's
"Rocket Man" playing)
폰이 울리네요
Sorry. My phone.
로켓 맨?
What is that?
Is that "Rocket Man"?
네, 벨소리요
Yeah, my ring tone.
제일 좋아하는 곡이에요
Kind of my favorite song,
"Rocket Man."
하워드
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
Howard,
후르트링이 눅눅해지고 있어
your Fruit Loops
are getting soggy!
나중에요
Not now!
누구야?
Who's that?
엄마요,
죄송해요
My mom. Sorry.
괜찮아,
후르트링
No problem... Fruit Loops.
공대언니 블로그
http://tbbt.tistory.com
== sync, corrected by elderman ==